<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="netPanzer - An Online Multiplayer Tactical Warfare Game">
  <section title="What is netPanzer?">
    <p>
      netPanzer is an online multiplayer tactical warfare game designed for
      FAST ACTION combat. Gameplay concentrates on the core -- no resource
      management is needed. The game is based on quick tactical action and unit
      management in real-time. Battles progress quickly and constantly as
      destroyed players respawn with a set of new units. Players can join or
      leave multiplayer games at any time.
    </p>

    <p>
      Official netPanzer development got basically halted in 1999,
      since 2002 netPanzer is available under the <a
      href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GNU GPL</a> and thus
      Free Software and a GNU/Linux port of netPanzer is ready.
    </p>
  </section>

  <subsection title="Features">
    <ul>
      <li>
        netPanzer is a game designed to fit into the real-time
        tactical game genre. It's art is based on realistic
        environments and vehicles. Battle will heat up as players
        challenge for territory, and without the need for resource
        management battles will emerge swiftly.
      </li>
    </ul>

    <subsubsection title="Network:">
      <ul>
        <li>Features a scalable client/server network architecture.</li>
      </ul>

      <ul>
        <li>Support from 1 to 100 players over the Internet or on LAN systems
          depending on the network connection type and game configuration (single/multi dedicated
          server vs. server-player, max number of units per player and so forth).
        </li>
      </ul>
      <ul>
        <li>Players will be able to join or leave multiplayer games at any time.</li>
      </ul>
    </subsubsection>

    <subsubsection title="Gameplay:">
      <ul>
        <li>Real-time action without the need to gather resources. </li>
        <li>Manually aim your units fire while they are moving to another
          location.</li>
        <li>Maps range in size from 10x13 to 64x85 640x480 size screens.</li>
        <li>Three modes of multiplayer combat; objective capture, frag limit, and
          time limit.</li>
        <li>Change screen resolutions on the fly to 640x480, 800x600 or 1024x768</li>
        <li>A customizable interface layout.</li>
        <li>MiniMap for quick viewing of the world.</li>
      </ul>
    </subsubsection>

    <subsubsection title="Special Effects:">
      <ul>
        <li>Particle system explosions, muzzle shots, missile trails, etc.</li>
        <li>Dynamic, real-time lighting.</li>
        <li>Translucent particles and shadows.</li>
      </ul>
    </subsubsection>
  </subsection>
</page>
