<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="netPanzer - An Online Multiplayer Tactical Warfare Game">
  <section title="FAQ - Frequently Asked Questions">
    <faq-list>
      <faq>
        <question>Where can I find public servers?</question>
        <answer>
          There are currently no public servers available, but if you
          want to play netPanzer and search for other players and
          servers, join the IRC channel <tt>#netpanzer</tt> at
          <tt>irc.freenode.net</tt>, you will find there players and
          developers and sometimes people will give you an IP to join
          a match.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>How many players does netPanzer support?</question>
        <answer>
          netPanzer has been designed around a scalable client/server network
          architecture and it should support from 1 to 100 players over the
          Internet or on LAN systems depending on the network connection type
          and game configuration (dedicated server vs. server-player, max number
          of units per player, fog of war, and so forth).
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>How do multiplayer games work?</question>
        <answer>
          There are three modes of multiplayer combat: Outpost, Frag Limit, or Time Limit.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>What are the controls for netPanzer like?</question>
        <answer>
          netPanzer uses a mouse and keyboard to manipulate units.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>How big are the game maps?</question>
        <answer>
          Maps range in size from 10x13 to 64x85 640x480 size screens.
        </answer>
      </faq>
      
      <faq>
        <question>What if I don't have a network or internet
          connection?</question> 

        <answer>
          A skirmish mode will be available for those without a ready
          network connection. The computer player available in skirmish
          mode can also be used in regular multiplayer games as
          well.
        </answer>
      </faq>
      
      <faq>
        <question>
          Is there camping in netPanzer? I mean, if there are no
          resources what is the object of the game?
        </question>

        <answer>
          This game was designed to make players fight--no sitting
          around waiting for your opponents to waste themselves in
          combat and then wiping them out. Players will be battling for
          outposts, so that they can increase their unit count.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>
          What happens when all of a players units are destroyed?
        </question>

        <answer>
          Every player respawns when their last unit is destroyed.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>How do I build more units, if there are no resources?</question>
        <answer>
          By capturing an outpost, a player can build more units. Each
          unit has a specific build time. A major strategy in the game
          will be capturing and holding onto outposts. Each outpost a
          player owns can produce units for the player.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>What is an Outpost?</question>
        <answer>
          An outpost is mainly a factory that produces units for the player who owns it.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>How can an Outpost game be won if players keep
          respawning?</question> <answer>By taking over a percentage of
          the outposts a player can win the game.</answer>
      </faq>

      <faq>
        <question>Will players be able to ally?</question>
        <answer>Yes, players can ally.</answer>
      </faq>
    </faq-list>
  </section>
</page>