<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="netPanzer - News">
  <section title="News">
    <news>
			<item date="23. Feb 2005">
				<p>Credits + Music</p>
				<p>I just realized that we weren't giving any credits to all the people
				that work and have worked on netpanzer (esp. Pyrosoft). No we have a
				credits section in the about page.</p>
				<p>While writing the credits I remembered that I had some contributed
				music lying around here for months. A big thanks and sorry for the late
				uploading to pronobozo. You can now grab
				<a href="http://download.berlios.de/netpanzer/netpanzer-music.zip">
				netpanzer-music.zip</a> and unzip it in your netpanzer directory or in
				<i>$HOME/.netpanzer</i>.</p>
				<p>PS: We're still searching for a new maintainer.</p>
			</item>
      <item date="12. Nov 2005">
        <p>Looking for a new maintainer</p>
        <p>The last months I was very busy with university and other open source
        projects I'm working on. So effectively netpanzer development has
        halted. I'm looking for someone to take over the netpanzer
        development. If you're interested write a mail to <a
        href="mailto:matze@braunis.de">matze@braunis.de</a>.</p>
      </item>
      <item date="27. Jan 2005">
        <p>NetPanzer 0.8 released</p>
        <p>Downloads available here: <a
                 href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">
                 http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250</a>.</p>
       <p>Changes:
            <ul>
                <li>Call this final release 0.8 to better reflect the state of
                development</li>
                <li>You can move the camera to a defined group by pressing group
                key twice</li>
                <li>Server shuts itself down instead of stying in an endless
                loop</li>
                <li>The -c command handles netpanzer:// URLs now</li>
                <li>Some additional infos are sent out by the server which help
                server browser</li>
                <li>Distribute cached palettes so that the first start should be
                faster now</li>
                <li>The code finally works on the Mac and probably other
                big-endian boxes</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
      </item>
                 
      <item date="10. Nov 2004">
       <p>Thanks to Tobias Blerch we now have a <a
       href="http://netpanzer.n-d-m.net">php serverbrowser</a> for
       netpanzer. Additional thanks goes out for Jan Brenner who setup the
       script on his server and created a nice template design for the output.
       </p>
      </item>
      <item date="8. Nov 2004">
       <p>netPanzer 0.2.0 release candidate 4</p>
       <p>This is a prerelease open for public testing. Especiacially the new
          ppc code needs more testing. I'd be happy about some feedback if it
          works or not (matze@braunis.de).
       </p>
       <p>Downloads available here: <a
         href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">
         http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250</a>.
         Changes:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>Really fixed Duell map</li>
        <li>Fixed servercrash introduced in rc3</li>
        <li>Fixed connecting to servers on different port than 3030</li>
      </ul>
      </item>
      <item date="3. Nov 2004">
        <p>netPanzer 0.2.0 release candidate 3</p>
        <p>This is a prerelease open for public testing. Especiacially the new
        ppc code needs more testing. I'd be happy about some feedback if it
        works or not (matze@braunis.de).
        </p>
        <p>Downloads available here: <a
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">
http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250</a>. Changes:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Fixed Duell map</li>
        <li>Fixed servers not always registering at all masterservers but only
        one</li>
        <li>Fixed some crashs in game</li>
        <li>Fixed several crashs and misbehaviour in the serverlist</li>
        <li>open a new console for win32 server and bot</li>
        <li>Fixed problem in log code that manifested on linux/ppc (thanks to
        Johannes Mockenhaupt for report+patch)</li>
        <li>Adding units with shift key now also works for groups and boxes
        (thanks to Rex Tsai for the patch)</li>
        <li>packet handling is more robust against malformed packets</li>
        <li>Added Support for pidfiles in server</li>
        <li>Wrote a HowTo on setting up a dedicated server</li>
        </ul>
      </item>
      <item date="15. Oct 2004">
        <p>netPanzer 0.2.0 release candidate 2</p>
        <p>This is a prerelease open for public testing. Especiacially the new
        ppc code is not tested yet. I'd be happy about some feedback if it
        works or not (matze@braunis.de).
        </p>
        <p>Downloads available here: <a
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">
http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250</a>. Changes:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>New masterserver protocol (next release of <a
                href="http://xqf.sf.net">xqf</a> will contain support for
                netpanzer)</li>
        <li>Added a serverconsole</li>
        <li>Fixed endianess problems. PPC users can play with x86 users
        now.</li>
        <li>The server creates logfiles now that can be used for statistics or
        reports on webpages</li>
        <li>Replaced SDL_net with custom socket wrappers.</li>
        <li>libxml2 replaced with simple ini parser</li>
        <li>gcc 3.4 fixes</li>
        <li>lots of bugfixes</li>
        </ul>
      </item>
      <item date="17. Mar 2004">
        <p>We're looking for someone who'd host a masterserver for netpanzer</p>
        <p>To avoid the current problems with irc in the future we'd like to
        setup a masterserver for netpanzer. So if you have a stable and reliable
        linux server and want to help an open-source game project, then we'd
        like to hear from you :)<br/>
        <b>Update:</b>I got 2 generous offers for hosting so next version will
        feature a nice stable masterserver system.</p>
      </item>
      <item date="10. Mar 2004">
        <h3><font color="red">Lobby Problems</font></h3>
        <p>The freenode network has some security scripts running that try to
        identify spam and clone bots. Unfortunately netpanzers server exactly
        match criterias of these scripts. To not cause more trouble on our
        favourite irc server we decided to move the lobby over to
        irc.quakenet.org (Note that the development channel #netpanzer will
        of course stay at freenode)</p>
        <p>You <font color="red">have to do 1 of the following things</font>:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Invoke this command:<br/>
                <tt>netpanzer --lobby_server=irc.quakenet.org</tt>
            </li>
            <li>Edit the <tt>netpanzer.xml</tt> file (you can typically find it
                    in $HOME/.netpanzer/config) and replace
                "irc.freenode.net:6667" with "irc.quakenet.org".
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p>Sorry for these inconveniences. Next release will have correct
        defaults.</p>
      </item>
      <item date="2. Mar 2004">
        <p>netPanzer 0.1.5 is available now:</p>
	<ul>
	    <li>emergency bugfix: mapcycling was actually broken</li>
	    <li>fixed bug where pressing "m" while chatting would
		toggle minimap display</li>
	    <li>Added an icon in .xpm format</li>
	</ul>
      </item>
      <item date="22. Feb 2004">
	<p>netPanzer 0.1.4 is available now:</p>
	<ul>
	    <li>It's possible to configure the mapcycle in the server</li>
	    <li>each player has a unique color on the radar (thanks
		    viras)</li>
	    <li>small fixes to make netpanzer run on win32</li>
	    <li>added a quickconnect option to the commandline. This is
	    usefull for external server browsers like <a
	    href="http://www.suselinuxsupport.de/index.php?location=download">
	    KNetpanzerBrowser</a>
	    </li>
	    <li>More smaller bugfixes and improvements</li>
	</ul>
      </item>
      <item date="05. Jan 2004">
        <p><a
        href="https://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">
        netPanzer 0.1.3</a> is available now:</p>

        <ul>
            <li>fix bug where the lobby view would always display 0/x players</li>
            <li>some robustness and usability fixes for the irc lobby code</li>
            <li>new slovakian flag</li>
            <li>lots of code cleanups and rewrites (and still lots more to do)</li>
            <li>unit spawnpoint can be choosen at the outposts now</li>
            <li>some small UI improvements</li>
            <li>reorganised build environment</li>
            <li>network packets are smaller and more robust now</li>
        </ul>

      </item>
      <item date="19. Dec 2003">
        We moved over to <a href="http://developer.berlios.de">berlios.de</a>.
        You can find the new homepage at <a href="http://netpanzer.berlios.de">
        http://netpanzer.berlios.de</a>.<br/>
        Along with the new site comes a <a
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/survey/survey.php?group_id=1250&amp;survey_id=31">survey</a>.
        Please take the little time to give us some feedback.
      </item>
      <item date="11. Nov 2003">

        <p><a
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">netPanzer
        0.1.2</a> is available now:</p>
        
        <ul>
          <li>A new lobby view and server browser has been added</li>
          <li>a man page has been added</li>
          <li>The deciated server reads it's setting from a configuration file now</li>
          <li>The bot player can now be started as a separate process.</li>
          <li>polish and swedish flag has been added (we happily accept more flags)</li>
          <li>several smaller bugfixes and improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </item>

      <item date="17. Oct 2003">
        People interested in a little multiplayer netPanzer session
        are welcome to join <tt>#netpanzer</tt> at
        <tt>irc.freenode.net</tt>, there you can find other players
        and developers.
      </item>

      <item date="14. Oct 2003">
        Release of netPanzer 0.1.1, fixes a number of issues that made
        0.1 not so much useable (checkboxes not clickable, crashes
        after outpost occupation)
      </item>

      <item date="10. Oct 2003">
        Release of netPanzer 0.1, it runs and compiles under GNU/Linux
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>
</page>
