<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page title="netPanzer - News">
  <section title="News">
    <news>
      <item date="22. Feb 2004">
	<p>netPanzer 0.1.4 is available now:</p>
	<ul>
	    <li>It's possible to configure the mapcycle in the server</li>
	    <li>each player has a unique color on the radar (thanks
		    viras)</li>
	    <li>small fixes to make netpanzer run on win32</li>
	    <li>added a quickconnect option to the commandline. This is
	    usefull for external server browsers like <a
	    href="http://www.suselinuxsupport.de/index.php?location=download">
	    KNetpanzerBrowser</a>
	    </li>
	    <li>More smaller bugfixes and improvements</li>
	</ul>
      </item>
      <item date="05. Jan 2004">
        <p><a
        href="https://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">
        netPanzer 0.1.3</a> is available now:</p>

        <ul>
            <li>fix bug where the lobby view would always display 0/x players</li>
            <li>some robustness and usability fixes for the irc lobby code</li>
            <li>new slovakian flag</li>
            <li>lots of code cleanups and rewrites (and still lots more to do)</li>
            <li>unit spawnpoint can be choosen at the outposts now</li>
            <li>some small UI improvements</li>
            <li>reorganised build environment</li>
            <li>network packets are smaller and more robust now</li>
        </ul>

      </item>
      <item date="19. Dec 2003">
        We moved over to <a href="http://developer.berlios.de">berlios.de</a>.
        You can find the new homepage at <a href="http://netpanzer.berlios.de">
        http://netpanzer.berlios.de</a>.<br/>
        Along with the new site comes a <a
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/survey/survey.php?group_id=1250&amp;survey_id=31">survey</a>.
        Please take the little time to give us some feedback.
      </item>
      <item date="11. Nov 2003">

        <p><a
        href="http://developer.berlios.de/project/showfiles.php?group_id=1250">netPanzer
        0.1.2</a> is available now:</p>
        
        <ul>
          <li>A new lobby view and server browser has been added</li>
          <li>a man page has been added</li>
          <li>The deciated server reads it's setting from a configuration file now</li>
          <li>The bot player can now be started as a separate process.</li>
          <li>polish and swedish flag has been added (we happily accept more flags)</li>
          <li>several smaller bugfixes and improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </item>

      <item date="17. Oct 2003">
        People interested in a little multiplayer netPanzer session
        are welcome to join <tt>#netpanzer</tt> at
        <tt>irc.freenode.net</tt>, there you can find other players
        and developers.
      </item>

      <item date="14. Oct 2003">
        Release of netPanzer 0.1.1, fixes a number of issues that made
        0.1 not so much useable (checkboxes not clickable, crashes
        after outpost occupation)
      </item>

      <item date="10. Oct 2003">
        Release of netPanzer 0.1, it runs and compiles under GNU/Linux
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>
</page>
